

Dilawar Hussain

House NE-4455, New Sultanpura Rawalpindi, Pakistan

+92 342 5218681

+92 345 5278759

engr.dilawarhussain@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/dilawar-hussain-297ab6105/

"Candidate with hands on experience on designing, installation, commissioning maintenance of domestic, commercial and industrial solar projects, publication on solar-grid integration issues, seeks a position in a renowned organization to enhance engineering skills by theoretical as well as pragmatic approach"

Education

Academic Qualifications.....

The University of Lahore

MS Electrical (Power) Engineering

COMSATS University

• BS Electrical (Power) Engineering, 2.88/4 CGPA

Punjab College of Information Technology

• Fsc (Pre-Engineering), 808/1100

Career Guidance Public School and College

• Matric, 793/1050

Islamabad, Pakistan

2017-Present

Abbottabad, Pakistan

2012-2016

Rawalpindi, Pakistan

2010-2012

Skardu, Pakistan

2007-2009

Publications.....

Solar-Grid Integration Issues: Overvoltage Dilemma

A 50 Hz grid system of ten buses with overcurrent/overvoltage protection system and a distribution feeder of three buses were developed in ETAP. The benefits and impacts of solar power injection were investigated and potential solution for the issue (overvoltage) was proposed. Further details are available at:

http://ssrn.com/abstract=2984567

JOB EXPERIENCE

Fouz International (<u>www.fouzintl.com</u>) Manager Technical & Operations Islamabad, Pakistan February 5th, 2018–Present

I have been working at **Fouz International Islamabad** which is a marketing Partner of **Hefei Jntech New Energy Co.Ltd. China** (http://www.intechenergy.com/).

My responsibilities are to;

- Manage technical and financial aspects of projects through ongoing job forecasting.
- · Provide coaching/counseling to foreman.
- Negotiate and resolve all customer concerns.
- Collaborate and communicate with technical team as needed.
- Provide technical assistance and resolve field issues.
- Prepare complete technical and financial bids of different government tenders.
- · Arrange site survey and prepare feasibility reports.
- Arrange technical team for installation and facilitate them to execute the project.
- Visit installation site to monitor either the project is progressing as per standards or not.

Akhter Solar Ltd. Islamabad (http://www.akhtersolar.com/)
Manager Sales & Operations

Islamabad, Pakistan February 5th, 2017–February 6th 2018

As a Manager Sales & Operations my core responsibilities were to;

- Enhance company sales by implementing different marketing tactics.
- Work on designing, commissioning and installation of Off-Grid, On-Grid, Hybrid and Netmetering solar systems, ranging from 1KVA to 100KW in different cities of Pakistan.
- Serve as a technical leader and manage several simultaneous projects.
- Work on designing, commissioning & installation of submersible solar water pumping systems under Punjab Irrigation Department.
- Prepare feasibility reports for different solar projects.
- Prepare technical and financial bids of various government projects related to solar system.
- Lead & provide technical assistance to the installation team for execution of different projects.
- Entertain site complaints of clients and fix their issues.
- Design & install solar power based water filtration plant. Also, design solar system for domestic, industrial and commercial customers.

Solar Sigma Ltd. Islamabad (<u>www.solarsigma.com</u>) Solar System Engineer

Islamabad, Pakistan January 20th, 2016–February 2017

As a Solar System Engineer I worked on designing, installation, commissioning & maintenance of domestic, commercial and industrial hybrid, on-grid and off-grid solar projects. One of my achievements was demonstration of net metering technology at Islamabad Electric Supply Company (IESCO) head office by installing 3-KW grid tied solar system. IESCO approved, first time at domestic level in Pakistan, net-metering technology in 2016.Prepared financial/technical bid and won the tender funded by United Nations Development Program (UNDP) named "Provision of Solar System for 58 Police Stations of KPK under Rule of Law program. Installed 1KVA to 100KW net metering systems at different cities of Pakistan.

Short Courses

Electrical Engineering Solutions International (EESINT) Pvt. Ltd Lahore Pakistan	Lahore
Programmable Logic Controller	2016
NICON Group of Colleges Dubai Plaza 6th Road Rawalpindi Pakistan	Rawalpindi
Spoken English (Advanced)	2014
Khyber Institute of Professional Skills Dubai Plaza 6th Road Rawalpindi Pakistan	Rawalpindi
• C++	2012
Khyber Institute of Professional Skills Dubai Plaza 6th Road Rawalpindi Pakistan	Rawalpindi
Computer Course	2012
Khyber Institute of Professional Skills Dubai Plaza 6th Road Rawalpindi Pakistan	Rawalpindi
Basic English Language	2012

Technical and Personal skills

PVsyst,ETAP,C++,Matlab, TeX,PLC and MS Office/Outlook/Excel/Power Point

Trainings/Workshops/Seminars

9th July, 2018 International Roving Seminar on Technical Innovations for Water & Power

The seminar was organized at Serena Islamabad by Ministry of Planning Development & Reforms Pakistan, Hefei Jntech New Energy Co.Ltd. China and Fouz International Ltd. Pakistan. I gave presentation on JNTECH Solar Water Pumping Inverters/Auxiliaries ,JNTECH Bidirectional Energy Storage Inverter & JNTECH Hybrid/Off grid Inverters.

Workshop on PCB Design

3rd & 4th June, 2013

I attended the workshop on PCB design organized by IEEE COMSATS University, Abbottabad.

Honors & Achievements

Scholarship

I did Bachelor of Electrical (Power) Engineering by Gilgit-Baltistan (GB) Government Scholarship. **Appreciation Letter**

For my best performance at Solar Sigma Ltd. Islamabad, I got appreciation letter from the company

References

Zia-Ur-Rehman

CEO at Fouz International, Islamabad Pakistan

Email: ceo@fouzintl.com (+92 3000991336, (051) 235 0091 Ext 2)

Nisar A Latif

CEO at Solar Sigma Ltd. Islamabad, Pakistan

Email: info@solarsigma.com (+92 3015356635, (051) 5421006)

Ammad Yousuf

General Manager at Akhtar Solar Islamabad, Pakistan

(+92 (300) 8321473, +92(0) 995-617205) Email: gm@akhter.co.uk

Dr. Jawad Saleem

Assistant Professor at COMSATS Institute of Information Technology (CIIT) Abbottabad, Pakistan Email: jawadsaleem@ciit.net.pk (+92 (335) 9110400)

Dr. Zahid Mehmood

Professor at The University of Lahore, Pakistan

Email: zahid.mehmood@ee.uol.edu.pk (+92 (333) 5585531)